# Andy del Valle

Seattle, WA | 661-319-4385 | andydelvalle89@gmail.com

Github: github.com/andydvalle | Portfolio: andydelvalle.dev | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andydelvalle/

### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

Software Engineer who enjoys being at the intersection of logic and creativity to design elegant websites. Experienced in JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, and React based programming. Previous healthcare and customer service experience allow me to bring strong skills in critical thinking, interpersonal communication, and project management

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, React Hooks, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Postgres, JSON, ActiveRecord, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Git

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Simple Care - Github | Video Demo | Live Demo

Medical care app to help caregivers manage their loved one's medications, health conditions, appointments, and clinics

- Developed backend and frontend to organize medical care using Ruby on Rails and React components
- Utilized JSON web tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Leveraged the National Library of Medicine API to create an autocomplete search table using CSS and React Hooks
- Implemented the design ideas of and collaborated with a UX Designer through Figma to improve user experience

### Message In a Bottle - Github | Video Demo | Live Demo

Mental Health/Journal app that allows users to anonymously send or receive messages to other writers around the world

- Created API with Ruby on Rails and Active Record for data persistence of messages, journals, and users
- Utilized Postgres to design database schema and coded database logic
- Designed frontend styling with Bootstrap and CSS for an elegant design to optimize user experience and navigation

# Seattle Bike Traffic- Github | Video Demo

Biking app that provides bike counter data allowing cyclists to visualize route information with relative graphs and reviews

- Used Socrata Open Data API using JSON to render monthly bike counter data into a line graph
- Built the comments feature using Ruby on Rails and ActiveRecord to associate them with specific bike counters
- Collaborated in a team setting that applied Gitflow to create multiple pull requests with each new feature

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Highline Medical Center**

Seattle, WA

Registered Nurse, Intensive Care Unit

11/2018 - 03/2020

- Cared for patients with life-threatening conditions and delivered medical interventions ordered by physician
- Handled critical care equipment such as ventilators, IV pumps, bedside monitors, and cooling machines
- Titrated continuous infusions and administered medications after calculating proper dosage based on assessments
- Charted nursing notes, vital signs, and interventions on EPIC, a cloud-based electronic health record

Kern Medical Center Bakersfield, CA

Hospital Staff Nurse I, Intensive Care Unit

01/2018 - 10/2018

- Adhered to best practices and strict hospital protocols set by evidenced based research
- Calculated correct dosage and administered medications after doing safety checks
- Used MediTech, an electronic medical record system

### Aira Tech Corp (remote)

San Diego, CA 05/2017 - 02/2018

Aira Agent

• Provided visual information to blind and visually impaired clients via Aira smart glasses/phone camera

Used orientation and mobility terminology to help clients navigate their surroundings

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

04/2020 - 07/2020

Bakersfield College

Bakersfield, CA

Associate Degree, Registered Nursing

12/2017